export let mcqdata = [
    {
        id : 1,
        question : 'HTML',
        answer : ' Hyper Text Markup Language'
    },
    {
        id :2,
        question : 'CSS',
        answer : 'Cascading Style sheet'
    },
    {
        id : 3,
        question : 'JavaScript',
        answer : ' It is a programming and Scricpting  Language'
    },
    {
        id :4,
        question : 'Types of tages',
        answer : 'Paired and Unpaired Tags'
    },
    {
        id :5,
        question : 'Attributes',
        answer : 'Attributes are the property of tag to change the behaviour of the tag'
    },
    {
        id :6,
        question : 'Tag',
        answer : 'Tags are used to add content on the webpage'
    },
    {
        id :7,
        question : 'Types of Attributes',
        answer : 'Local and Global Attribute'
    },
    {
        id :8,
        question : 'Lists',
        answer : 'Ordered list, Unordered List, Description List'
    },
    {
        id :9,
        question : 'Tags of Table',
        answer : 'table, tbody, thead, tfoot, tr, th, td'
    },
    {
        id :10,
        question : 'Hyperlink',
        answer : 'It is used to show links or URL on the webpage. when you click on the link it will navigate you to another webpage. To create link we use anchor tag i.e., < href="....path or url...."a/>'
    },
    {
        id :11,
        question : 'Types of Hyperlink',
        answer : 'Internal and External'
    },
    {
        id :12,
        question : 'Inline Elemnt',
        answer : 'Ocupies only required width '
    },
    {
        id :13,
        question : 'Block Element',
        answer : 'Occupies full width of the wepage'
    },
    {
        id :14,
        question : 'Example of Inline Element',
        answer : 'img tag,input tag, button tag, '
    },
    {
        id :15,
        question : 'Example of Block Element',
        answer : 'div tag'
    },
    {
        id :16,
        question : 'Semetic Tag',
        answer : 'Sementic tags for used for giving meaning to the layout'
    },
    {
        id :17,
        question : 'Non Sementic Tag',
        answer : 'these are meaningless tags '
    },
    {
        id :19,
        question : 'Forms',
        answer : 'Forms are used to collect the data from users'
    },
    {
        id :20,
        question : 'Use of required atribute',
        answer : 'Required attribute are used to make the input field mandatory to fill'
    },
    {
        id :21,
        question : 'Difference between Div and span tag',
        answer : 'Div tag are block level elemnt, it takes the full width of the webage but span tag of inline level element, it only takes required width'
    },
    {
        id :22,
        question : 'Current version of CSS',
        answer : 'CSS3'
    },
    {
        id :23,
        question : 'Who introduced CSS?',
        answer : 'CSS is introduced by Hakon Wium Lie'
    },
    {
        id :24,
        question : 'when CSS is introduced',
        answer : 'CSS is introduced in the year 1994'
    },
    {
        id :25,
        question : 'What is CSS?',
        answer : 'CSS is used to give designs and styles to the webpage'
    },
    {
        id :26,
        question : 'Types to apply CSS ',
        answer : 'Inline CSS, Internal CSS, External CSS'
    },
    {
        id :27,
        question : 'Inline CSS',
        answer : 'To apply inline CSS we use style attribute within the tag and the designs will be applied only to that tag.'
    },
    {
        id :28,
        question : 'Internal CSS',
        answer : 'To apply internl CSS we use style tag within the head tag and designs will be applied by using one of the selectors.'
    },
    {
        id :30,
        question : 'External CSS',
        answer : 'To apply external CSS we need to create a css file with .css extension. By using one of the selectors we can apply designs.'
    },
    {
        id :31,
        question : 'Selectors',
        answer : 'Selectors are used to select one or more tags for applying designs'
    },
    {
        id :32,
        question : 'Types of Selectors',
        answer : 'ID selector, Class Selector, Group selector, Universal Selector,Attribute selector, Pseudo Selector,Combinators'
    },
    {
        id :33,
        question : 'Box Model',
        answer : 'Its a layout of an html element which is created by default on the webpage which includes content, padding, border and margin.'
    },
    {
        id :34,
        question : 'Margin',
        answer : 'Margin are the space outside the border or space between two html elements'
    },
    {
        id :35,
        question : 'Display Property',
        answer : 'Display Property is used to convert inline elements to block elements and vice- versa'
    },
    {
        id :36,
        question : 'Display Flex',
        answer : 'It should always be applied to he parent tag.childern elements are converted to inline elment. By using flex we can allign the elements horizontally and vertically.'
    },
    {
        id :37,
        question : 'Position',
        answer : 'Position property are to move the elements or to place the element wher it is required to be placed'
    },
    {
        id :38,
        question : 'What is JavaScript?',
        answer : 'It is a scripting and programming language which is used in cliend side as well as server side .'
    },
    {
        id :39,
        question : 'who introduced Js?',
        answer : 'It is introduced by Brenden Eitch in the year of 1995'
    },
    {
        id :40,
        question : 'Types of Js',
        answer : 'Internal and External Js.'
    },
    {
        id :41,
        question : 'Variables',
        answer : 'Veriables are memory blocks which is used to store the datas.'
    },
    {
        id :42,
        question : 'Variable Keywords in js',
        answer : 'var, let and const'
    },
    {
        id :43,
        question : 'Datatypes',
        answer : 'Datatypes are nothing but the type of data which we can assign to variable.'
    },
    {
        id :44,
        question : 'Types of Datatypes in js',
        answer : 'Primitive and Non premitive Datatype'
    },
    {
        id :45,
        question : 'Primitive datatypes in js',
        answer : 'Number, string, boolean, null, undefined, symbol'
    },
    {
        id :46,
        question : 'Operators ',
        answer : 'Operator is a predefined symbol which will perform some specific operation on the operands present in LHS and RHS.'
    },
    {
        id :47,
        question : 'Difference between == and ===',
        answer : '== - it checks only the value but === - it cgecks the value and the datatype of the variable'
    },
    {
        id :48,
        question : 'Control Statements',
        answer : 'It is used to execute a set of statement based on the condition -- if , if else, if else ladder, switch'
    },
    {
        id :49,
        question : 'Loops',
        answer : 'Loops are used to execute a block of code or statements repetadely until the condition becomes false. --- for, while, do while, forEach, for of, for in'
    },
    {
        id :50,
        question : 'Functions',
        answer : 'Functions are block of statements which are used to do some specific operation or tasks.'
    },
]